Part Heaven... Part Hell... Pure Havana.
Cuba is a action, drama, romance film directed by Richard Lester.
A British mercenary arrives in pre-Revolution Cuba to help train the corrupt General Batista's army against Castro's
guerrillas while he also romances a former lover now married to an unscrupulous plantation owner.
Maj. Robert Dapes, played by Sean Connery.
Alexandra Lopez de Pulido, played by Brooke Adams.
Larry Gutman, played by Jack Weston.
Capt. Raphael Ramirez, played by Héctor Elizondo.
Donald Skinner, played by Denholm Elliott.
Gen. Bello, played by Martin Balsam.
Cuba is a 1979 American adventure thriller film directed by Richard Lester and starring Sean
Connery, portraying the build-up to the 1958 Cuban Revolution, filmed in Panavision.
Lester developed the film out of a conversation with a friend, with
significant influence from the 1942 film Casablanca.
The film explores themes of cuba, politics, revolution, plantation, mercenary.
The tone is emotional and intense.